Sandeep Chauhan

+91-6005030657

Website
LinkedIn Github

sandeepsajan0@gmail.com Moradabad, India

Summary I'm a Software Developer with 1+ years of professional experience and 3+ years of learning experience. I have majorly worked with Python and Django. I also had some good hands with Reactjs, HTML, CSS. I have good problem-solving skills. I am quick and self-learner.

Experience

Backend Developer at **Eoraa**

Apr 2020-Present

- Develop REST APIs for the backend of a Key-Door Companies Management App. Deploy and Manage project on AWS with Nginx.
- Implement some important features like auto-creation of a subdomain for every client, send a payment link via mail to the client to continue with their subscription.
- Developed APIs for mobile applications and the CMS for a travel consultant company.
- Worked with some of the Django concepts for query optimization, to deal with migrations. Maintain the projects on GCP with multiple environments.

Full-stack developer(contract) at Remote Inning

Jan 2020 - March 2020

- Developed the backend APIs with the JWT Authentication and the other best practices.
- Integrate Wagtail CMS with a static site template, create its models, templates, template-tags and etc.
- Upgrade the cookiecutter-django-foundation with the foundation site's version.

Full-stack developer Intern at Spoonshot

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Scaled and improved performance of web crawlers, implemented using Python/Django. Add multiple functionalities to make it simpler.
- Deployed a proxy-manager for scraping framework on the Django server with Redis.
- Dockerize the scraping framework and scale it with MongoDB, celery workers, and AWS. Also, implement monitoring systems with Grafana and InfluxDb.

Google Summer of Code Student at Hydra Ecosystem

April 2018 - Aug 2018

- Python-based implementation of <u>Hvdra Client</u>.
- Implemented Hydra Client with the datastore Redis which also works as a cache for Hydrus.

Open Source Contribution

- hydra-python-agent I was the main contributor who has built this project.
 Implemented Redis as a graph database using redisgraph and Cypher. Also created a Docker env., write tests, use designing patterns, etc.
- hydrus Add UUID in the database and also add auto-documentation using sphinx and fix some easy issues.
- <u>hydra-astrodemo</u> Created a demo for hydra-client using flask which also using the hydra-parser and hydrus server.
- http-apis.github.io Write documentation for all the work done by me and also for some other projects related to my work.

Projects

Backend APIs

It contains are the basic APIs with almost all the best practices like JWT Auth, use of SendGrid to send activation mail, User Groups and Permissions, usage of settings file in different environments, and the best way to define API endpoints and most importantly it is also live on Heroku

Go Web App

A Web app implemented with Golang using Redis as a database having features routing, authentication, middleware, comments, error handling. It is a good reference for beginners because of its modules and good structure.

Reactjs Projects

- Calculator
- o router-sample
- friends_passion(Beginner-friendly project to iterate over JSON data)
- ReactSwapi_Api(React app to consume API and show data of swapi.co)

Friends

An anonymous web chat app implemented with Python, Django, Reactjs with database sqlite3 have some great functionalities like authentication, public and private groups(without showing users), API's, messaging/posting, API's data presenting using Reactjs.

Social Networking

A blogpost web app that is implemented using Python, Django, and PostgreSQL as a database having features like authentication, manage to profile, blog posting (with date and name). It is also deployed on Heroku.

Education

• Bachelor of Technology(2016-2020(expected))

Shri Mata Vaishno Devi University, Katra, India

Miscellaneous

• Student guide and Program Host at The CodeClub, SMVDU.

Skills

Backend Development: Python(Django, Wagtail), Golang **Frontend Development:** React.js, HTML and CSS, JS **Databases:** PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, MongoDB, sqlite

Operating System: Linux(ubuntu)

Other tools: Git, Bash, AWS, Docker, Celery, RabbitMQ, Grafana, InfluxDb,